Tarek Mahmud Utsho

As a highly creative, resourceful, collaborative and result oriented individual I have a drive to take challenges head on and leave an impact. I want to overcome every challenge and use every opportunity while working for an organization to gain as much knowledge and experience as possible.



tarek.mahmud.utsho1@gmail.com

01680552567



Dhaka, Bangladesh

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration

Institute of Business Administration, University of Dhaka

01/2020 - 12/2021

Maior

Marketing

Bachelor of Business Administration

East West University

01/2015 - 04/2019 3 62

Maior

Marketing

Higher Secondary Certificate

BCIC College

2012 - 2014 5.00

Secondary School Certificate

Monipur High School

2007 - 2012 5.00

WORK EXPERIENCES

Business Development Executive SaveUp IT Ltd

10/2019 - 12/2019

Market visit to convince clients. Maintain relationships with existing clients. Develop shortterm and long-term sales objectives and strategic plans.

Intern

British American Tobacco Bangladesh

06/2019 - 09/2019

Kept physical files and digitized records organized for easy updating and retrieval by authorized team members. Worked in Battle of Mind Activation. Helped with the assessment

Feature Writer

Daily Samakal

I used to write Chakri Bazar in feature page Chakri Niye. (Part time)

Translator Borderline

2015 - 2020

Used to translate press releases. (Part time)

SKILLS

Case Studies

Brand Management

Strategic Marketing

Consumer Behavior

International Marketing

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Finalist at ADWIZ 2017, Marketing Based Competition by BRACU

Quarter-finalist at Brief-Case 2016, Intra Sales based Business Case Competition organized by EWU

Finalist at Intra Analytics 2017, Digital marketing-based competition organized by EWU

Organizer Head, East West University Management Project Exhibition -2017

Organizer at Presentation Grooming Session Summer, 2017

LANGUAGES

Bangla

Full Professional Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

REFERENCES

Sheikh Morshed Jahan, Professor, IBA, University of Dhaka, smj.strategy@gmail.com, +8801828649875

Mashruha Zabeen, Senior Lecturer, East West University mhz@ewubd.edu, +8801791925474